# Jingcheng Wang

# Front-End Developer | JavaScript | ReactJS

**SUMMARY** 

Front-End Developer with 14 years experience in web development. Proficient in JavaScript and ReactJS, with intermediate skills in NextJS and TypeScript. Experience in team leadership and collaboration, with addition of numerous individually completed projects. Efficient project management skills to deliver on time and achieve client satisfaction.

**EXPERIENCE** 

# **Front-End Developer**

## Australia Southworld Media

## Aug 2016 - Feb 2024

Sydney, NSW

Responsible for frontend design and development for media related web application

- Developed a web app that promotes upcoming events using JavaScript, PHP and
- Later migrated the events app to ReactJS
- Developed a web app that collects articles published on the employer's Wechat Official Account (Chinese social media platform) and provides additional search and categorize functions
- Developed websites for employer and partnering companies and organisations, utilising different frameworks and platform according to the clients' needs.

# **Business Support Technician**

## Thales Australia

mar 2010 - Jul 2016

Sydney, NSW

Responsible for a data repository system used across departments based on

- Led team to develop a SharePoint based data repository system that replaced the existing work process for data collection
- Regular maintenance and updates as more departments were brought into the system
- Developed web flows to integrate reporting across departments and automate work processes within different departments
- Utilized Javascript to extend functionalities such as data visualization

## Webmaster

# University of Sydney Table Tennis Club

mar 2010 - Dec 2012

Sydney, NSW

Responsible for design and maintenance for the club website

- Built the club website from scratch using HTML and CSS
- Later migrated the website to Wordpress

# **EDUCATION**

# Master of Philosophy (Engineering and IT)

University of Sydney

i 2013 - 2015 😯 Sydney, NSW

# **Bachelor of Engineering (Software) and Bachelor of Arts (Chinese)**

University of Sydney

iii 2008- 2012 Sydney, NSW

LANGUAGES

**English** 

Native •••• Chinese (Mandarin) Native ●●●●

Sydney, NSW

+61 466832322 / +86 15666111306

ingcheng-wang-2010.github.io

github.com/jingcheng-wang-2010

in jingcheng-wang-63415a173

#### STRENTHS



## **Web development Expertise**

Proficient in JavaScript and ReactJS, coded efficient, maintainable web applications that resulted in 30% performance improvement



#### Adaptability

Selection and migration of websites to different platforms and frameworks as to the clients' needs



#### Self-starter & Fast Learner

Learnt SharePoint and Visual Basic on the job. Gave suggestions and developed new functionalities to SharePoint system using my expertise in Javascript

#### **SKILLS**

Javascript ReactJS **Typescript PHP NextJS Bootstrap** CSS/SASS Java iOuery

Wordpress Git / Github Python

SharePoint SharePoint Designer

Visual Basic

#### **CERTIFICATION**

# **Front End Development Libraries**

provider: freeCodeCamp (^)

## **JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures**

provider: freeCodeCamp (^) **Responsive Web Design** provider: freeCodeCamp (^)

### REFERENCE

Stephen Jia

Marketing Manager

Australia Southworld Media

+61 426 958 890

tong.jia@southworldmedia.com

Stedroy Farrell

Business Quality Manager

Thales Australia

+61 409 912 195

stedroyf@gmail.com